Do you have DesignaKnit?
Did you know that you could use it
with your LK 150 machine,
a Brother KX 350, or any knitting machine
that doesn't have working electronics?
In this tutorial,
we'll discuss some of the possibilities.
We are assuming that you're
familiar with the  DesignaKnit basics the purpose of this tutorial is
to give you an overview of how you can use
it with non-patterning machines
or non-electronic machines,
no matter what machine you're using.
Standard Garment Styling and Original
Pattern Drafting are a powerful
way to create garment shapes.
The idea is to use the graphical interface
to create shapes in the
dimensions that you want.
Now, there are many, many tutorials
online for creating shapes.
Once you've created your shape,
you don't need electronics to knit it.
You can print out your knitting
instructions in the format
that works for you.
After confirming your gauge, click >File
>Print and select the format you want.
Garment text or garment notation are
the most common formats for use
in this case.
You can even use them for hand knitting.
Another option is to use the Interactive
Knitting feature in DesignaKnit.
For this example,
I'll use my raglan sweater shapes
and after confirming my gauge, I'll
select the Interactive Knitting Tool.
Now, for manual machines,
this tool can be used in two ways.
First, you can purchase the SSL USB cable.
This cable will allow Designaknit to sense
the movement of your knitting carriage as
you pass the carriage back and stitch.
DesignaKnit increments the graphic
display and instructs you what
to do while you're knitting.
Now you don't have the cable,
you can still use Interactive Knitting
simply manually increment the graphic
display using the arrows in the software
or the arrow keys on your keyboard
so you could knit along a few rows
and then up arrow, up arrow, up arrow
to the row that you're on manually.
Either way, you follow the images
in the display in Interactive Knitting
to increase, decrease and do whatever
else you need to shape your knitting.
Now, you can also use DesignaKnit
for stitch patterning on these
manual and non-electronic machines.
Even if you have a manual machine,
you use the same interactive Knitting
interface to manually select the needles.
For example,
I've opened a Fairisle stitch pattern.
You can follow along the stitch pattern
in the lower section of the screen
to select your needles.
To work your Fairisle manually,
you can use the cable and magnet or
manually advance the rows with the arrows.
Now, this may be a better example
using tuck. On a manual machine,
you can select the needles to tuck
according to the lower section
of Interactive Knitting.
You'll just follow the diagram row by row,
selecting your needles
and setting your carriage to tuck.
In this example
again, you could use the cable and let
DesignaKnit record what row you're
on or just increment the rows manually.
Now finally, you can combine all of this
and integrate the stitch pattern
with the shaping pieces and let
interactive knitting give you both shaping
instructions and stitch patterning
instructions at the same time.
Increase left one.
Increase right one.
I hope I piqued your curiosity about using
DesignaKnit with your
non electronic machine.
This wasn't intended as
a DAK tutorial in any way.
Only an introduction as to what is
possible, no matter what machine you use.